Kris Xu

Toronto, ON 416-887-6599 miaoxuxo@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Specialize in Data Analytics & Reporting, Result Orientated Business Intelligence Consultant and Data Analyst with 4+ years industry experience in Financial Service, Real Estate and Retail. Apart from possessing exceptional analytical and problem solving skills, Kris is highly motivated individual with rich experience in being bridge between business and technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language: SQL, Python, VBA/Marco, R

Application System: Banking system, Salesforce, ZenDesk, PeopleSoft

Business Intelligence Products: Microsoft Power BI, Google Analytics, Tableau, Advanced Excel

Database & Platform: Microsoft SQL Server, **Azure SQL DB**, PostgreSQL Industry: Bank, Real Estate, Retail, Marketing and consulting

EXPERTISE

- ✓ CRM, Marketing
- ✓ Financial Analysis
- ✓ Banking System, Data & Process
- ✓ Business Workflow

- ✓ Business Requirement Analysis (BRD)
- ✓ Data Analytics & ETL
- ✓ Dashboard and Reporting
- ✓ Process Automation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CRM Analyst Innovative Vision Marketing Inc.

- Worked with the business stakeholders to ensure regulatory requirements and operating procedures are fully conducted
- ♦ Investigated customer data quality, completeness, information key & executing status across various systems & databases
- Prepared Business Require Document for KYC reporting project, which delivered integrated view of Customer information
- Created ETL Specification on data sources, Table and Column selections, data cleansing rules for developers & testers.

Tools: Customer ADM, Business BMO, ZenDesk, Salesforce, Azure SQL DB, PostgreSQL, TSQL Python, Power BI, Excel

Analyst, Debt Capital Market Yunnan Metropolitan Real Estate Development Company Ltd.

Mar 2018 - Oct 2020

Feb 2021 - Present

- Analyzed Corporate Financial Statements using finance methodologies for maintaining business activities and evaluating overall financial performance; Delivered financial performance reports to underwriters and credit rating institutions.
- ♦ Created operating performance dashboards in Power BI for roadshow presentation to various stakeholders & investors.
- ♦ Analyzed operating and sales data in SQL database and validated the data integrity gaps.
- Managed forecasting & procurement activities and conducted bond market research & analysis.
- Simplified the reporting process by introducing technical solution to reduce duplicated work.
- ♦ Monthly profit & loss report automation process design with Access and Excel.
- Data Quality analysis, summarized the method to resolve duplication issue in data warehouse.

Tools: Power BI, Access, Excel, VBA, SQL

Data Analyst Investors & Treasury Services, RBC

Nov 2016 - Nov 2017

- Designed ETL process for master data cleansing and governance of securities profile using python.
- ♦ Conducted continuous enhancement of SQL script and VBA coding for improving the efficiency of daily transactions.
- ♦ Investigated month-end interest accruals for high-risk bonds, and adjusted bond profiles in automated way.
- ♦ Processed daily transactions, and priced U.S. equities with EOD price in a timely and accurate manner in various systems.
- ♦ Enhanced Master data management process of Money Market and OTC securities in internal platforms and systems.

Tools: SQL, Python, VBA, Gplus, Milvus, Mpower, Bloomberg

- ♦ Provided commercial lending supports for syndicated and bilateral loans targeting the New York market.
- ♦ Investigated facilities, prioritized daily transactions, and cooperated with other financial institutions to ensure transactions operate appropriately in terms of portfolio risk.
- Conducted portfolio analysis, collaborated with the risk management team to verify client profiles and track operations for high-risk clients.
- ♦ Improved daily transaction system with analysis on derived month-end interest accruals.

Tools: RBC Acbs, Swift, Excel, VBA

Account Service Agent

Mortgage and Loan Department, RBC

Apr 2015 - Aug 2015

- ♦ Analyzed individual churn rate clients with current account profiles through daily transaction data.
- Applied Credit Risk Modeling using Logistic Regression in R to reduce the Bad Loan Error Rate for loan application.
- Ensued effective resolution, follow-upped all enquires, and liaise with appropriate parties to resolve escalated queries.
- ♦ Involved in ongoing daily tasks, and input data into the internal platform as required.

Tools: RBC Banking System, R, Excel, VBA

EDUCATION

Master in Financial Economics Carleton University Sep 2012 – Jun 2014
Bachelor in Business, International Accounting Yunnan University of Finance and Economics Sep 2005 - Jun 2009

CERTIFICATES

Microsoft Power BI - DAX | Tableau Training for Data Science Advanced

Python for Financial Analysis and Algorithmic Trading | Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Boot Camp

Google Analytics Basic and Advanced Certificate | Microsoft Excel - Advanced Excel Formulas & Functions